Nithees Kumar R

(Full Stack Java Developer)

Email: <u>nitheeskumar0612@gmail.com</u>
Phone Number: (+91) 90924-29000

Career Summary

A passionate working professional with 2 years of experience and proven knowledge in various technologies. I am passionate about learning new technologies and applying them to projects to solve real-time problems. I worked with various technologies on different projects. I am a quick learner, adaptable, and ready to learn anything based on the project requirements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer Analyst (PA) | Cognizant | June 2023 - PRESENT

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing the business process and client requirements to prepare the Behavior-Driven Development (BDD).
- Writing Test scripts using programming languages like java and frameworks like Appium, Cucumber, and TestNG.
- Automating both Android and iOS devices using Android studio, Xcode.
- Executing all mobile features integrating with sauce lab and lambda test applications.
- Involving in creating Test cases, Test Scenarios, and Test Data for business requirements.
- Involving in SAP ECC, SAP HANNA, pGAdmin tools for test data preparation and validation.
- > Designing the test cases to validate the requirements for DSMC mobile applications for both Android and iOS.
- Responsible for tracking the scope of Change Request (CR) starting from the Test Plan phase to the Deployment phase.
- > Involving in defect re-test and defect tracking to closure.
- Responsible for preparing Weekly Test Status reports and Test Execution reports and share to the stakeholders.
- Involving in new requirement discussions with businesses and coming up with test design and strategy.

Programmer Analyst Trainee (PAT) | Cognizant | June 2022 - June 2023

Roles and Responsibilities:

- > Designed and Developed web applications using front-end technologies like ReactJS, and back-end technologies like SpringBoot and MySql.
- > Developed stand-alone CRUD based Restful services using three-layer architecture.
- Developed Rest Endpoints based on the functional requirements.
- Learned and implemented unit testing using frameworks like Junit and Mockito.
- > Tested APIs using tools like PostMan client.
- > Implemented JWT Authentication for the APIs.
- ➤ Used GitHub for storing, tracking and version control.

Genc Intern | Cognizant | December 2021 - June 2022

Roles and Responsibilities:

- As part of the internship, I was trained in FSE Java. During this internship, I learned a lot of technologies.
- > Frontend HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular.
- > Backend Java, Microservices, SpringBoot, Spring MVC, Spring Data JPA, Spring Restful, MySql.
- ➤ In the final project, I took the responsibility of developing a Rest API which is a microservice- based application, and frontend is developed using the Angular framework.

EDUCATION

B.Tech (IT)	Thiagarajar College of Engineering, Madurai	Anna University (Autonomous)	2022	8.40 (CGPA)
Diploma	K L Nagaswamy Memorial Polytechnic College, Madurai	DOTE	2019	79%
X	Royal Vidyalaya Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Madurai	State Board	2015	77.2%

SKILLS

- > Java
- > Spring Boot
- React JS
- > HTML
- > CSS
- JavaScript
- > SQL

PROJECTS

PROJECT TITLE	DESCRIPTION
	A database application that automates the management of
	stocks at the pharmacy using PHP database. It warns the user
Wholesale Pharmacy Management System	of the needed medicine based on the availability and
	frequent series based ordering of medicine in a timely
	manner. Asks for confirmation from the admin when logged
	in, with a dedicated user interface for the admin as well as
	consumers.
	Concepts used: Mysql
	To develop a web application for viewing and tracking the
Covid Patient Tracker and Supporting Application	status of covid-19 cases in and across the country and to
	provide different supporting features that are needed during
	the pandemic period.
	Concepts used: HTML,CSS

CERTIFICATION

- ➤ Hello React React Training for JavaScript Beginners || Provided by Udemy
- ➤ Web Development HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node, React, MongoDB, Web3 || Provided by- Udemy
- ➤ Microsoft Cloud Certification- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals || Provided by- Microsoft
- ➤ Microsoft Cloud Certification- Microsoft Azure Developer Associate || Provided by- Microsoft
- ➤ GitHub Certification- GitHub Foundations || Provided by- GitHub
- ➤ GitHub Copilot Java React CI/CD Technology for Developers || Provided by- Cognizant
- ➤ Postman REST API Testing || Provided by- Udemy

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Nithees Kumar R Date of Birth: 06-12-1999

Gender: Male

Mobile: +91 90924-29000

Email: nitheeskumar0612@gmail.com

Total Exp: 2 years

Language Known: English, Tamil

Place: Madurai, Tamil Nadu

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Yours Faithfully, Nithees Kumar R